A Finding Aid to the Betty Parsons Gallery records and personal papers, circa 1920-1991, bulk 1946-1983, in the Archives of American Art AAA.parsbett
Archives of American Art
- Sales and Inventory Records, 1946-1981; Series 5; (Boxes 25-28, 51; 2.9 linear feet)
  - Sales and Purchases, 1946-1981; 5.1
    - Sales Invoices by Buyer (Box 25)
      - Sales Invoices, Moo-Moy, 1949-1974 (Box 26, Folder 23)
      - Sales Invoices, Mul-Mye, 1953-1971 (Box 26, Folder 24)
      - Sales Invoices, Museum of Modern Art, 1949-1974; (2 folders) (Box 26, Folder 25-26)
      - Sales Invoices, Nat-Neu, 1950-1981 (Box 26, Folder 27)
      - Sales Invoices, New-New York, 1952-1972 (Box 26, Folder 28)
      - Sales Invoices, Nic-Noy, 1949-1970 (Box 26, Folder 29)
      - Sales Invoices, Oak-Osh, 1949-1975 (Box 26, Folder 30)
      - Sales Invoices, Oss-Owi, 1949-1976 (Box 26, Folder 31)
      - Sales Invoices, Pag-Pav, 1952-1979 (Box 26, Folder 32)
      - Sales Invoices, Pea-Pey, 1948-1974 (Box 26, Folder 33)
      - Sales Invoices, Phe-Pol, 1951-1973 (Box 26, Folder 34)
      - Sales Invoices, Poo-Pow, 1953-1974 (Box 26, Folder 35)
      - Sales Invoices, Pra-Pur, 1950-1975 (Box 26, Folder 36)
      - Sales Invoices, Quaker Oats Company, 1969-1972 (Box 26, Folder 37)
      - Sales Invoices, Rac-Rev, 1950-1975 (Box 26, Folder 38)
      - Sales Invoices, Rey-Rig, 1950-1972 (Box 26, Folder 39)
      - Sales Invoices, Ril-Rob, 1949-1973 (Box 26, Folder 40)
      - Sales Invoices, Roc-Rog, 1949-1971 (Box 26, Folder 41)
      - Sales Invoices, Rol-Rosc, 1946-1974 (Box 26, Folder 42)
      - Sales Invoices, Rose-Rosw, 1951-1975 (Box 26, Folder 43)
      - Sales Invoices, Rub-Rya, 1950-1975 (Box 26, Folder 44)
      - Sales Invoices, Sac-San, 1946-1975 (Box 26, Folder 45)
      - Sales Invoices, Sar-Schl, 1948-1970 (Box 26, Folder 46)
      - Sales Invoices, Schn-Schw, 1949-1973 (Box 26, Folder 47)
      - Sales Invoices, Sco-Sha, 1953-1975 (Box 26, Folder 48)
      - Sales Invoices, She-Sil, 1952-1974 (Box 26, Folder 49)
      - Sales Invoices, Sim-Siv, 1951-1973 (Box 26, Folder 50)
      - Sales Invoices, Ski-Smith, H., 1951-1973 (Box 26, Folder 51)
      - Sales Invoices, Smith, J.-Smithsonian, 1949-1973 (Box 26, Folder 52)
      - Sales Invoices, Smo-Son, 1956-1975 (Box 26, Folder 53)
      - Sales Invoices, Spa-Sta, 1946-1975 (Box 26, Folder 54)
      - Sales Invoices, Ste-Sti, 1947-1974 (Box 26, Folder 55)
      - Sales Invoices, Sto-Swa, 1951-1980 (Box 26, Folder 56)
      - Sales Invoices, Stroud, W.B. Dixon, 1967-1980 (Box 26, Folder 57)
      - Sales Invoices, Tak-Tel, 1949-1973 (Box 26, Folder 58)
      - Sales Invoices, Tho-Tol, 1948-1975 (Box 26, Folder 59)
      - Sales Invoices, Too-Tru, 1947-1976 (Box 26, Folder 60)
      - Sales Invoices, U, 1948-1973 (Box 27, Folder 1)
      - Sales Invoices, V, 1952-1981 (Box 27, Folder 2)
      - Sales Invoices, Wag-Wat, 1949-1975 (Box 27, Folder 3)
      - Sales Invoices, Web-Wei, 1954-1975 (Box 27, Folder 4)
      - Sales Invoices, Weld-Wells, 1962-1974 (Box 27, Folder 5)
      - Sales Invoices, Wes-Wil, 1952-1975 (Box 27, Folder 6)
      - Sales Invoices, Wim-Wur, 1948-1975 (Box 27, Folder 7)
      - Sales Invoices, Whitney Museum of American Art, 1947-1975 (Box 27, Folder 8)
      - Sales Invoices, X-Z, 1951-1974 (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - Sales Invoices - Chronological (Box 27)
      - Sales Invoices, 1963 (Box 27, Folder 10)
      - Sales Invoices, 1966-1967 (Box 27, Folder 11)
      - Sales Invoices, 1968; (2 folders) (Box 27, Folder 12-13)
      - Sales Invoices, 1969; (2 folders) (Box 27, Folder 14-15)
      - Sales Invoices, 1970 (Box 27, Folder 16)
      - Sales Invoices, 1971 (Box 27, Folder 17)
      - Sales Invoices, 1972 September-December (Box 27, Folder 18)
      - Sales Invoices, 1973 (Box 27, Folder 19)
      - Sales Invoices, 1974-1979 (Box 27, Folder 20)
      - Sales Invoices, 1980-1981 (Box 27, Folder 21)
    - Sales Invoices by Invoice Number (Box 27)
      - Sales Invoices, nos. 3-199, 1969 (Box 27, Folder 22)
      - Sales Invoices, nos. 200-298, 1969 (Box 27, Folder 23)
      - Sales Invoices, nos. 300-399, 1970-1971 (Box 27, Folder 24)
      - Sales Invoices, nos. 400-471, 1972 (Box 27, Folder 25)
      - Sales Invoices, nos. 472-573, 1972 (Box 27, Folder 26)
      - Sales Invoices, nos. 574-610, 1972-1973 (Box 27, Folder 27)
      - Sales Invoices, nos. 611-667, 1973 March-October (Box 27, Folder 28)
      - Sales Invoices, nos. 668-709, 1973-1974 (Box 27, Folder 29)
      - Sales Invoices, nos. 710-746, 1974 January-March (Box 27, Folder 30)
      - Sales Invoices, nos. 747-787, 1974 April-September (Box 27, Folder 31)
      - Sales Invoices, nos. 788-799, 1974 October-December (Box 27, Folder 32)
      - Sales Invoices, nos. 800-843, 1975 January-July (Box 27, Folder 33)
      - Sales Invoices, nos. 844-915, 1975-1976 (Box 27, Folder 34)
    - Sales Invoices for Overdue Accounts, 1975-1976; (2 folders) (Box 27, Folder 35-36)
    - Sales Invoices - Cancelled or Unpaid, 1969-1978 (Box 27, Folder 37)
    - Sales and Commissions Daybook, 1946-1947; (incomplete) (Box 27, Folder 38)
    - Expenses and Commissions Daybook, 1953-1969 (Box 27, Folder 39)
    - Commissions Daybook, 1970-1981 (Box 27, Folder 40)
    - Price and Insurance Daybook, 1965 November (Box 27, Folder 41)
    - Summary of Museum Sales, circa 1946-1952 (Box 27, Folder 42)
    - Sales Summaries for Pollock, Reinhardt, and Rothko, 1946-1955 (Box 27, Folder 43)
    - Sales Summaries, 1963; (See Box 51) (Box 27, Folder 44)
    - Sales Record Ledger Book, 1946-1958; (incomplete) (Box 27, Folder 45)
    - Sales Journal, 1972 January-August; (ledger sheets, double page format) (Box 27, Folder 46)
    - Sales Journal, 1972-1973; (ledger sheets, double page format) (Box 27, Folder 47)
    - Sales Journal, 1973-1974; (ledger sheets, double page format) (Box 27, Folder 48)
    - Sales Journal, 1974-1975; (ledger sheets, double page format) (Box 27, Folder 49)
    - Sales Journal, 1975-1976; (ledger sheets, double page format) (Box 27, Folder 50)
    - Purchases of Works of Art, 1950-1965 (Box 27, Folder 51)
    - Purchases of Works of Art, 1966-1967 (Box 27, Folder 52)
    - Purchases of Works of Art, 1968-1975 (Box 27, Folder 53)
    - Oversize, Sales Summaries, 1963; (Scanned with Box 27, F44) (Box 51 (sol))
  - Artist Accounts, 1946-1980; 5.2
    This subseries contain the records of financial transactions between the gallery and artists, primarily the amount of commission that the gallery received from the artist/sale, and expenses charged back to the artists for exhibitions, advertising, and framing. Artist accounts include ledger sheets, lists, sales and expense invoices, and an expenses daybook.
    Ledger sheets and invoices are arranged alphabetically by name of artist, while lists are arranged chronologically.
    - Artist Accounts - Expenses Daybook, 1946-1953 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Artist Accounts and Exhibition Inventories, 1950-1962; (3 folders) (Box 28, Folder 2-4)
    - Artist Expenses and Commissions, 1972-1975; (2 folders) (Box 28, Folder 5-6)
    - Artist Accounts - Individual, circa 1973 (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Artist Accounts - Group Lists, 1965-1981 (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Artist Sales and Expenses Invoices; A-B, 1956-1980 (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - Artist Sales and Expenses Invoices; C, 1968-1974 (Box 28, Folder 10)
    - Artist Sales and Expenses Invoices; F, 1963-1980 (Box 28, Folder 11)
    - Artist Sales and Expenses Invoices; G, 1963-1980 (Box 28, Folder 12)
    - Artist Sales and Expenses Invoices; H, 1963-1980 (Box 28, Folder 13)
    - Artist Sales and Expenses Invoices; J, 1968-1974 (Box 28, Folder 14)
    - Artist Sales and Expenses Invoices; K, 1963-1974 (Box 28, Folder 15)
    - Artist Sales and Expenses Invoices; L, 1963-1979 (Box 28, Folder 16)
    - Artist Sales and Expenses Invoices; M-N, 1962-1980 (Box 28, Folder 17)
    - Artist Sales and Expenses Invoices; O, 1963-1976 (Box 28, Folder 18)
    - Artist Sales and Expenses Invoices; P, 1963-1980 (Box 28, Folder 19)
    - Artist Sales and Expenses Invoices; R, 1963-1974 (Box 28, Folder 20)
    - Artist Sales and Expenses Invoices; S, 1962-1981 (Box 28, Folder 21)
    - Artist Sales and Expenses Invoices; T, 1966-1980 (Box 28, Folder 22)
    - Artist Sales and Expenses Invoices; V-W, 1963-1980 (Box 28, Folder 23)
  - Consignment and Loan Records, circa 1948-1983; 5.3
    Found here are documents concerning loans to or from the gallery for sales and exhibitions. Although the Betty Parsons Gallery occasionally sent works on consignment to other galleries, the majority of consignments were to museum art rental and sales galleries, most notably the Museum of Modern Art's Art Lending Service. The gallery also loaned works to various museums and institutions for exhibitions and participated in the Art in Embassies program. The files contain correspondence, invoices, receipts, daybooks, and loan forms. Most documents contain standard data on the work of art, including title, artist, medium, creation date, and dimensions. Invoices for consignments to the gallery also contain the name and address of the original owner.
    Files within this subseries are arranged alphabetically by individual or institution except for the daybooks, which are arranged chronologically.
    - Consignments to Betty Parsons Gallery (Box 28)
      - A-B, circa 1963-1983 (Box 28, Folder 24)
      - C-G, circa 1963-1983 (Box 28, Folder 25)
      - H-J, circa 1971-1979 (Box 28, Folder 26)
      - K-P, 1949, circa 1970-1980 (Box 28, Folder 27)
      - R-Z, circa 1959-1983 (Box 28, Folder 28)
      - Lists, circa 1975-1976 (Box 28, Folder 29)
      - Returned, circa 1971-1983; (4 folders) (Box 28, Folder 30-33)
      - Sold, circa 1963-1983; (2 folders) (Box 28, Folder 34-35)
    - Consignments from Betty Parsons Gallery (Box 28)
      - Baltimore Museum of Art, Sales and Rental Gallery, circa 1962-1973 (Box 28, Folder 36)
      - Museum of Modern Art, Art Lending Service, circa 1951-1978; (5 folders) (Box 28, Folder 37-41)
      - Miscellaneous Galleries and Institutions, circa 1964-1983; (3 folders) (Box 28, Folder 42-44)
    - Loan Daybook, circa 1960-1965 (Box 28, Folder 45)
    - Loans In/Out Daybook, 1965 June-November (Box 28, Folder 46)
    - Loans In/Out Daybook, 1965-1966 (Box 28, Folder 47)
    - Loans to Institutions (Box 28)
      - American Federation of Arts, circa 1948-1970 (Box 28, Folder 48)
      - Art in Embassies Program, 1966-1979 (Box 28, Folder 49)
      - Museum of Modern Art, New York, circa 1953-1980 (Box 28, Folder 50)
      - Smithsonian Institution, Washington, DC, 1966-1982 (Box 28, Folder 51)
      - Whitney Museum of American Art, New York, 1975-1978 (Box 28, Folder 52)
      - Miscellaneous A-E, circa 1974-1979 (Box 28, Folder 53)
      - Miscellaneous F-G, circa 1975-1978 (Box 28, Folder 54)
      - Miscellaneous H, 1975-1978 (Box 28, Folder 55)
      - Miscellaneous I-J, 1970-1980 (Box 28, Folder 56)
      - Miscellaneous M, 1965-1979 (Box 28, Folder 57)
      - Miscellaneous N-R, 1972-1979 (Box 28, Folder 58)
      - Miscellaneous S, circa 1960-1976 (Box 28, Folder 59)
      - Miscellaneous U-V, 1953-1978 (Box 28, Folder 60)
      - Miscellaneous W-Z, 1972-1979 (Box 28, Folder 61)
  - Gallery Inventories, 1973-1980; 5.4
    This series consists of inventories in the form of notebooks and individual sheets that partially document the gallery's stock of art at distinct periods. There are a number of inventories of the work of individual artists. The Gallery and Warehouse Inventory of 1979 appears to be the only comprehensive record. It consists of loose sheets and A-Z tabbed dividers from a small binder. Information is arranged alphabetically by artist. This inventory also includes works from Betty Parson's private collection, which are identified by a "BP" in the left-hand margin.
    - Gallery Inventory, 1978 (Box 28, Folder 62)
    - Gallery and Warehouse Inventory, 1979 (Box 28, Folder 63)
    - Miscellaneous Inventories by Artist, 1973-1980 (Box 28, Folder 64)
- General Business and Financial Records, 1946-1983; Series 6; (Boxes 28-38; 9.6 linear feet)
  Records that provide an overview of the gallery's general business operations and financial transactions include general ledgers, paid bills, receipts, tax returns, storage records, shipping receipts, bank statements, check stubs and cancelled checks. Financial records concerning gallery stock are located in the sales and inventory files.
  This series is arranged into six subseries:
  6.1: Cash Disbursements and Receipts, circa 1965-1983
  6.2: Shipping and Storage Records, 1956-1983
  6.3: In/Out Slips, 1982-1983
  6:4: Legal Records, 1946-1978
  6.5: Tax Records, 1956-1977
  6.6: Banking Records, 1966-1982
  Not all of the records in this series have been scanned, specifically cash disbursements and receipts, tax records, and banking records.
  - Cash Disbursements and Receipts, circa 1966-1983; 6.1; (Not scanned)
    This subseries houses receipts and ledgers that record the gallery's routine financial transactions for goods and services. Scattered receipts, principally those for framing services, include information about works of art. The ledgers record annual accounts of cash disbursements and receipts, including sales. However, sales and purchases of works of art are documented more fully in Sales and Inventory Records, and those records are easier to interpret.
    Ledger books are arranged chronologically. Receipts are minimally processed and arranged in loose chronological order; within folders receipts are grouped together by vendor.
    - Cash Disbursements and Receipts Ledger, 1965; (See Box 51) (Box 28, Folder 65)
    - Cash Disbursements and Receipts Ledger, 1966; (See Box 51) (Box 28, Folder 66)
    - Cash Disbursements and Receipts Ledger, 1967; (See Box 51) (Box 28, Folder 67)
    - Cash Disbursements and Receipts Ledger, 1968; (See Box 51) (Box 28, Folder 68)
    - Cash Disbursements and Receipts Ledger, 1969 (Box 28, Folder 69)
    - Cash Disbursements and Receipts Ledger, 1970 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - Cash Disbursements and Receipts Ledger, 1971 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - General Ledger, 1972 January-August (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - General Ledger, 1972-1973 (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - Financial Statements and Documentation, circa 1973-1974 (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - Sales Invoices (non-art), 1977-1983 (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - Resale Certificates, 1965-1966 (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - Gallery Space Rental Receipts, 1974-1977 (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - Petty Cash Receipts, 1968 (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - Receipts, circa 1963-1969 (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - Receipts, 1970 (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - Receipts, circa 1971; (7 folders) (Box 29, Folder 12-18)
    - Receipts, circa 1972; (3 folders) (Box 29, Folder 19-21)
    - Receipts, circa 1973-1976; (9 folders) (Box 29, Folder 22-30)
    - Receipts, circa 1973-1976; (5 folders) (Box 30, Folder 1-5)
    - Receipts, circa 1977-1980; (24 folders) (Box 30, Folder 6-29)
    - Receipts, circa 1977-1980; (4 folders) (Box 31, Folder 1-4)
    - Receipts, circa 1981-1983; (22 folders) (Box 31, Folder 5-26)
    - Oversize, Cash Disbursements and Receipts Ledger, 1965; (See Box 28, F65) (Box 51 (sol))
    - Oversize, Cash Disbursements and Receipts Ledger, 1966; (See Box 28, F66) (Box 51 (sol))
    - Oversize, Cash Disbursements and Receipts Ledger, 1967; (See Box 28, F67) (Box 51 (sol))
    - Oversize, Cash Disbursements and Receipts Ledger, 1968; (See Box 28, F68) (Box 51 (sol))
  - Shipping and Storage Records, circa 1956-1983; 6.2; (Not scanned)
    These files contain correspondence, receipts, and record books from shipping and storage companies. Additional shipping and storage receipts can be found within the cash disbursements and receipts subseries.
    - Beverly Storage Company, Inc., Correspondence and Receipts, 1968 (Box 31, Folder 27)
    - Hague Art Delivery, Correspondence and Receipts, 1968-1977 (Box 31, Folder 28)
    - Morgan Manhattan Storage, Correspondence, 1951-1969 (Box 31, Folder 29)
    - W.R. Keating, Correspondence and Receipts, 1956-1982 (Box 31, Folder 30)
    - Storage Receipts, Cirker's Hayes Warehouse, 1973-1965 (Box 31, Folder 31)
    - Shipping Receipits from Loans, 1977-1979 (Box 31, Folder 32)
    - Shipping Receipts, New York State, circa 1973-1979 (Box 31, Folder 33)
    - Shipping Receipts, Outside New York, circa 1969-1979 (Box 31, Folder 34)
    - Miscellaneous Shipping Receipts, circa 1960-1983; (7 folders) (Box 32, Folder 1-7)
    - UPS Pickup Record Book, 1979 March-October (Box 32, Folder 8)
    - UPS Pickup Record Book, 1979-1980 (Box 32, Folder 9)
    - UPS Pickup Record Book, 1980-1981 (Box 32, Folder 10)
    - UPS Pickup Record Book, 1981 February-September (Box 32, Folder 11)
    - UPS Pickup Record Book, 1981-1982 (Box 32, Folder 12)
    - UPS Pickup Record Receipts, 1982-1983 (Box 32, Folder 13)
  - In/Out Slips, 1982-1983; 6.3; (Not scanned)
    These files record the movement of works of art to and from the gallery for the purposes of consignment, exhibition, and removal to off-site storage and restoration. Slips indicate name and address of recipient or sender and titles, artists, dates, and dimensions of the art work. Reasons for transfer, values and notes about condition are included on some slips.
    - In/Out Slips, 1981-1982 (Box 32, Folder 14)
    - In Slips 1982-1983 (Box 32, Folder 15)
    - In Slips 1983 January-April (Box 32, Folder 16)
    - Out Slips, 1982 (Box 32, Folder 17)
    - Out Slips 1983 April-June (Box 32, Folder 19)
    - Out Slips, 1983 May-June (Box 32, Folder 20)
    - Out Slips, 1983 June-July (Box 32, Folder 21)
  - Legal Records, 1946-1978; 6.4
    Scattered legal documents in this subseries include a standard gallery - artist contract, a copy of the 1974 lease for the gallery space at 24 West 57th Street and the minutes concerning the incorporation of the Parsons-Truman Gallery in 1974, an offshoot of the Parsons Gallery for showing works on paper. Additionally there are records from miscellaneous court cases. Of particular interest is the file on the lawsuit Parsons initiated against Sidney Janis over the space that they shared on the 5th floor of 15 East 57th Street, New York.
    - ADAA Gallery-Artist Agreement, 1962-1967 (Box 32, Folder 22)
    - Gallery Leases, 1947-1977 (Box 32, Folder 23)
    - Business Certificate, 1946 (Box 32, Folder 24)
    - Parsons-Truman Gallery Incorporation, 1974 (Box 32, Folder 25)
    - Sidney Janis v. Betty Parsons Court Case, 1962-1963 (Box 32, Folder 26)
    - Miscellaneous Court Cases, 1960-1978 (Box 32, Folder 27)
    - New York State Department of Labor Notices, 1948-1978 (Box 32, Folder 28)
  - Tax Records, 1956-1977; 6.5; (Not scanned)
    This subseries houses federal, state, and city tax returns and supporting documentation.
    - Federal, State and State Employer's Quarterly Returns, 1964-1971 (Box 32, Folder 29)
    - Federal, State and State Employer's Quarterly Returns, 1973-1975 (Box 32, Folder 30)
    - Employee Tax Returns and Receipts, 1965-1972 (Box 32, Folder 31)
    - New York State Unemployment and Disability Insurance, 1964-1977 (Box 32, Folder 32)
    - New York City and State Sale Tax Returns, 1964-1970 (Box 32, Folder 33)
    - Occupancy Tax Returns, 1963-1975 (Box 32, Folder 34)
    - Pallroll and Sales Taxes, 1972 (Box 32, Folder 35)
    - Payroll and Sales Taxes, circa 1973-1974 (Box 32, Folder 36)
    - Pallroll and Sales Taxes, circa 1974-1976 (Box 32, Folder 37)
    - Miscellaneous Tax Documents, 1956-1964 (Box 32, Folder 38)
    - Tax Worksheets, 1965 (Box 32, Folder 39)
    - Tax Worksheets, 1966-1967 (Box 32, Folder 40)
    - Tax Worksheets, 1968 (Box 32, Folder 41)
    - Tax Documents, 1968-1970 (Box 32, Folder 42)
    - Tax Documents, 1970 (Box 32, Folder 43)
    - Tax Documents, 1971-1974 (Box 32, Folder 44)
  - Banking Records, 1966-1982; 6.6; (Not scanned)
    This subseries houses bank statements, cancelled checks, and check stubs from the gallery's business account at Manufacturers Hanover Trust Company.
    Files are arranged by format and then chronologically. Within folders, cancelled checks are arranged in order of check number.
    - Bank Statements and Cancelled Checks (Box 33)
      - Manufacturers Hanover Trust, nos. 3871-4560, 1966-1967; (5 folders) (Box 33, Folder 1-5)
      - Manufacturers Hanover Trust, nos. 4561-5262, 1968; (6 folders) (Box 33, Folder 6-11)
      - Manufacturers Hanover Trust, nos. 4196, 5259-5989, 1969; (5 folders) (Box 33, Folder 12-16)
      - Manufacturers Hanover Trust, nos. 4355, 5920-6558, 1970 (Box 33, Folder 17)
      - Manufacturers Hanover Trust, nos. 4355, 5920-6558, 1970; (5 folders) (Box 34, Folder 1-4)
      - Manufacturers Hanover Trust, nos. 6559-7145, 1971; (5 folders) (Box 34, Folder 5-9)
      - Manufacturers Hanover Trust, nos. 7142-7499; 101-529, 1972; (4 folders) (Box 34, Folder 10-13)
      - Manufacturers Hanover Trust, nos. 530-1124, 1973; (4 folders) (Box 34, Folder 14-17)
      - Manufacturers Hanover Trust, nos. 1125-1636, 1974; (4 folders) (Box 35, Folder 1-4)
      - Manufacturers Hanover Trust, nos. 1637-3043, 1975; (4 folders) (Box 35, Folder 5-8)
      - Manufacturers Hanover Trust, nos. 3044-3565, 1976; (4 folders) (Box 35, Folder 9-12)
      - Manufacturers Hanover Trust, nos. 3566-4181, 1977; (4 folders) (Box 35, Folder 13-16)
      - Manufacturers Hanover Trust, nos. 4182-4709, 1978; (4 folders) (Box 36, Folder 1-4)
      - Manufacturers Hanover Trust, nos. 4710-5223, 5498, 1979; (4 folders) (Box 36, Folder 5-8)
    - Check Binders and Stubs, (Not scanned) (Box 36)
      - Manufacturers Hanover Trust, nos. 4490-4990, 1967-1968 (Box 36, Folder 9)
      - Manufacturers Hanover Trust, nos. 4990-5490, 1968-1969 (Box 36, Folder 10)
      - Manufacturers Hanover Trust, nos. 5490-5981, 1969-1970 (Box 36, Folder 11)
      - Manufacturers Hanover Trust, nos. 6000-6500, 1970 (Box 36, Folder 12)
      - Manufacturers Hanover Trust, nos. 6500-7000, 1970-1971 (Box 37, Folder 1)
      - Manufacturers Hanover Trust, nos. 7000-7500, 1971-1972 (Box 37, Folder 2)
      - Manufacturers Hanover Trust, nos. 101-600 ("special"), 1972-1973 (Box 37, Folder 3)
      - Manufacturers Hanover Trust, nos. 101-601, 1972-1973 (Box 37, Folder 4)
      - Manufacturers Hanover Trust, nos. 1446-1601, 1974 (Box 37, Folder 5)
      - Manufacturers Hanover Trust, nos. 1601-2101, 1974-1975 (Box 37, Folder 6)
      - Manufacturers Hanover Trust, nos. 1958-3357, 1975-1976; (2 folders; loose check stubs) (Box 37, Folder 7-8)
      - Manufacturers Hanover Trust, nos. 3358-3495, 1975-1976 (Box 37, Folder 9)
      - Manufacturers Hanover Trust, nos. 3500-4000, 1976-1977 (Box 38, Folder 1)
      - Manufacturers Hanover Trust, nos. 4000-4500, 1977-1978 (Box 38, Folder 2)
      - Manufacturers Hanover Trust, nos. 4500-5000, 1978-1979 (Box 38, Folder 3)
      - Manufacturers Hanover Trust, nos. 5500-6000, 1980-1981 (Box 38, Folder 4)
      - Manufacturers Hanover Trust, nos. 6000-6500, 1981-1982 (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - Manufacturers Hanover Trust Check Register, 1974-1981 (Box 38, Folder 6)
- Betty Parsons Personal Papers, circa 1927-1991; Series 7; (Boxes 38-51; 11.5 linear feet)
  This series documents the more personal and professional activities of Betty Parsons through early curatorial files from her work at Wakefield Gallery and Mortimer Brandt Gallery, biographical files, family papers, correspondence, pocket diaries, writings, photographs, printed materials, and financial records. Parsons' extensive personal papers also include files that provide an overview of her own career as an artist as well as her extensive private art collection.
  The Betty Parsons Papers series is arranged into 10 subseries:
  7.1: Early Curatorial Files, circa 1940-1958
  7.2: Biographical Material, circa 1928-1983
  7.3: Correspondence, circa 1932-1983